<funclist>

<func name="isPresent" sig="isPresent(rolename)">
  Return True if the a value for the named time series param is present at this time slice.
  Returns false if there is no value, or if there is a value but it is flagged as MISSING.
  <br/>
  The rolename argument should be a String name of a time series role in this algorithm.
  <br/>
  See also: isMissing, isRejected, isGoodQuality, isQuestionable
  This function may only be called inside a time slice.
</func>
<func name="isQuestionable" sig="isQuestionable(rolename)">
  Return True if the time series param at this time slice is flagged as questionable. 
  Returns false otherwise.
  <br/>
  The rolename argument should be a String name of a time series role in this algorithm.
  <br/>
  See also: isMissing, isRejected, isGoodQuality
  This function may only be called inside a time slice.
</func>
<func name="isRejected" sig="isRejected(rolename)">
  Return True if the time series param at this time slice is flagged as rejected. 
  Returns false otherwise.
  <br/>
  The rolename argument should be a String name of a time series role in this algorithm.
  <br/>
  See also: isMissing, isQuestionable, isGoodQuality
  This function may only be called inside a time slice.
</func>
<func name="isMissing" sig="isMissing(rolename)">
  Return True if there is no sample for the named
  time series param at this time slice. Returns true if there is one.
  <br/>
  The rolename argument should be a String name of a time series role in this algorithm.
  <br/>
  See also: isQuestionable, isRejected, isGoodQuality
  This function may only be called inside a time slice.
</func>
<func name="isGoodQuality" sig="isGoodQuality(rolename)">
  Return True if the time series param at this time slice is flagged as good quality -- 
  that is, it is not missing, questionable, or rejected. Returns false otherwise.
  <br/>
  This function may only be called inside a time slice.
  <br/>
  The rolename argument should be a String name of a time series role in this algorithm.
  See also: isQuestionable, isRejected, isGoodQuality
</func>

<func name="datchk" sig="datchk(rolename)">
  Performs a DATCHK screening on the passed input parameter value at this time slice.
  The quality flags are set on the input parameter, and may be subsequently checked
  by the isQuestionable, isRejected, or isGoodQuality functions.
  <br/>
  This function may only be called inside a time slice.
  <br/>
  Example:
<![CDATA[
        datchk('input1')
        if (isGoodQuality('input1')):
            setOutputAndQual('output1', input1.value, input1.qual)
]]>
</func>

<func name="screening" sig="screening(rolename)">
  Performs a CWMS screening on the passed input parameter value at this time slice.
  The quality flags are set on the input parameter, and may be subsequently checked
  by the isQuestionable, isRejected, or isGoodQuality functions.
  <br/>
  This function may only be called inside a time slice.
  <br/>
  Example:
<![CDATA[
        screening('input1')
        if (isGoodQuality('input1')):
             setOutputAndQual('output1', input1.value, input1.qual)
]>
</func>

<func name="setOutput" sig="setOutput(outputTsParm, value)">
  Sets the named output parameter to the specified value.
</func>
<func name="setQual" sig="setQual(TsParm, qual)">
  Sets the quality flags of the named time series parameter.
  This is most often used to set an output parameters flags from the flags of
  an input parameter, such as:
    setQual('outParm', inParm.qual)
</func>
<func name="setOutputAndQual" sig="setOutputAndQual(outputTsParm, value, qual)">
  Sets the named output parameter to the specified value. Also sets the
  quality bits to the value passed.
</func>

<func name="isNew" sig="isNew(rolename1)">
  Returns true if any of the named parameters was either a trigger 
  for this run of the computation, or it was just computed and flagged to write. 
  Return false otherwise.  Any number of inputs can be named.
  <br/>
  This can be used to skip unneeded processing steps in a multi-step computation.
  Consider a comp with 2 inputs and one output. input1 determines input2. Both
  then determine output:
  <br/>
<![CDATA[
	if isNew('input1'):
		value = some math using input1.value
		setOutput('input2', value)
	value = some math using input2.value and maybe also input1.value
	setOutput('output', value)
]]>
</func>
<func name="runningAverage" sig="runningAverage(rolename, duration, [co])">
  Perform a running average of the specified time series parameter over the specified
  duration. Example: runningAverage(stage_rev, "6Hours") will return a running average
  of the time series for stage_rev over the past 6 hours.
  A third string parameter may be supplied indicating whether the boundary values at the
  beginning and end of the period should be included. Square brackets [] indicate
  that the boundary values ARE included. Parentheses () indicate that they should NOT
  be included. For example: runningAverage(stage_rev, "6Hours", "(]") means to do
  the 6 hour running average that includes THIS value but not the one 6 hours ago.
  Note that this is the default if the third argument is not supplied.
  This function will throw NoSuchObjectException if duration or boundaries are invalid.
  This function will throw NoValueException if there are no rolename values within
  the specified duration.
</func>
<func name="changeSince" sig="changeSince(rolename, duration)">
  Return the change in the specified parameter compared to the historical value at
  the specified duration. Example: changeSince('storage', '6Hours') will return the change
  in the time series for storage compared to the value 6 hours ago.
  <br/>
  Can throw NoValueException if there is no value at the specified duration ago,
  and the system can't derive one through interpolation.
</func>
<func name="rating" sig="rating(specID, indep1, indep2, ...)">
  Perform a rating and return the result. The first argument is the spec ID for the
  CWMS-resident rating. Subsequent arguments are the independent variables. CWMS
  allows up to 9 independent variables in a rating.
</func>
<func name="rdbrating" sig="rdbrating(tabfile, indep)">
  Perform a rating using an RDB file and return the result. The first argument is the name of the
  table file. The second argument is the independent variable.
</func>
<func name="tabrating" sig="tabrating(tabfile, indep)">
  Perform a rating using an simple table file and return the result. The first argument is the name of the
  table file. The second argument is the independent variable.
</func>
<func name="debug3" sig="debug3(msg)">
  Write a DEBUG3 level message to the log.
  Will only appear if code is running in debug level 3 mode.
</func>
<func name="debug2" sig="debug2(msg)">
  Write a DEBUG2 level message to the log.
  Will only appear if code is running in debug level 2 or higher mode.
</func>
<func name="debug1" sig="debug1(msg)">
  Write a DEBUG1 level message to the log.
  Will only appear if code is running in debug level 1 or higher mode.
</func>
<func name="info" sig="info(msg)">
  Write a INFO level message to the log.
</func>
<func name="warning" sig="warning(msg)">
  Write a WARNING level message to the log.
</func>

<func name="lookupMeta" sig="rating(locationID, paramName)">
  (NOT IMPLEMENTED) Lookup the named parameter at the specified location and return its value.
</func>
<func name="abortComp" sig="abortComp(msg)">
  Aborts the computation with an error message. Can be thrown before, within, 
  and after time slices to abort the entire run of the computation. No data is 
  written from an aborted computation, even if setOutput has previously been called.
  Use the Python exit() function to exit a script without throwing an error.
</func>

</funclist>
